

PROFILE

rafael.h.escobar@proton.me

ith a little more than a decade of experience working as a Graphic Designer, his skills have served from the cultural sector to some small/indie/corporate businesses, including governmental organizations. This gave him a panoramic scope to approach visual communication from different angles, and also from a 'customer service' perspective. He's been working on the web side of things since the second half of 2016, and today he's developing an interest in leadership, User Experience (UX), Branding, and the fundamentals of accessibility.

EDUCATION & LANGUAGES

UNIVERSIDAD DE BOGOTÁ JORGE TADEO LOZANO

Bachelor's Degree in Graphic Design. Octobe 30th2014.

THE BRITISH COUNCIL BOGOTÁ

Advanced speaking, reading and listening. Good grammar. SPANISH (native)

Excellent writting & grammar.

DOMÉSTIKA

Basic principles to design brands. (in progress) Smartbrands, Brand Consulting. 2023.

EXPERIENCE

Ago 2020 - Dec 2022 SUPERINTENDENCE OF INDUSTRY AND COMMERCE

Role: Designer / Webmaster.

Was a bridge between the communications office (OSCAE) and the I.T department to manage content on different instances, to propose/develop and hand out some structure changes (custom fields, blocks & views) for both the organization's website and Intranet according to the 'gov.co' guidelines, and also gave general support by documenting and repoting functionality, usability & accessibility issues across the web platforms.

Built and maintained the monthly podcast NotiSIC, wrote case studies to improve content types from the CMS user side, delivered interactive content for bimonthly publications, generated wireframes for internal apps, designed the UI and Appstore mockups for the mobile application "SIC a la Mano" and built/sent custom mailings using MailChimp's features.

Jul 2016 - Mar 2020 PIXEL CLUB SAS

Role: Graphic/web designer & webmaster.

Focused on the content management and the visual design for some websites built with Drupal. Also wrote the html, CSS and developed custom fields, blocks and views for those. Clients: Santo & Seña, UniAndes, ACM, Bupa, SIC. More contributions: wireframing processes, landing page designs to display special products and some writing (in spanish) related to products, music & photography.

Ago 2015 - Mar 2016 ARTICULADOS, COMUNIC. DIGITAL

Role: Graphic Designer

Created images for social media posts, layout designs for presentations and anual/management reports which were much appreciated for the following clients:
Bogotá's Commerce Chamber creative branches (ARTBO, BOmm & Artecámara), BIFF (Bogotá International Film Festival) 1st Edition, Ambulante Documentary Film Festival, and Spanish film Exhibition (MCE).

2012 - Present GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Have worked mostly on projects for print, presentations (ppt + Keynotes), website designs for small and corporate businesses, and also have collaborated on artistic projects under Victor Escobar's wing back in 2010 and 2012 (Tráquira - Paisacres / Blanca Nieve) by helping to manufacture some of the pieces displayed on some of his exhibitions.

When Rafael is not doing design work for clients, he likes to take photos and explore design techniques on his own, mostly as a hobby.

INTERESTS

BOOKS

Good Design is a Tough Job (Strichpunkt Design) Gemini Man (Richard Steinberg), The Treasures of Pink Floyd (Glenn Povey) Youth (J.M. Coetzee). The Buying brain. The Universe in Your Hand (Christophe Galfard).

ARTISTS

Salvador Dalí, Victor Escobár, Vik Muniz, Leonardo Da Vinci, H.R., Giger, Omar Rayo.

COLOMBIAN GRAPHIC DESIGNERS

Lucho Correa, Dickén Castro, César Puertas and David Consuégra.

GRAPHIC DÉSIGNERS FROM THE WORLD

Stefan Sagmeister, Eddie Opara, Tobias Van Schneider, Michael Bierut y Bradley G. Munkowitz among others.

SKILLS



"Whoever drives a car can see the detail from the road, but he cannot see the landscape.

Whoever pilots an airplane sees the landscape, but he cannot see the detail of the road.

On the other hand, whoever flies a helicopter can see the detail of both."

-Lair Ribeiro-

"WITHOUT MUSIC, LIFE WOULD BE A MISTAKE." F. Nietzsche

Blues, Rock & their descendants. For long working sessions: Trip Hop or electronic music (ambient, house, minimal), and sometimes absolute silence is a must.

:MOVIES?

Sure! Let'stalk about whar we've got in common.

REFERENCES

Nicolás Rey Gallego & Eduardo Silva

Project Managers
Pixel Club S.A.S.

Natalia Gnecco

Social communicator and Journalist / Blogger EL TIEMPO - Superintendence of Industry and Commerce.

Alejandro Arteaga P.

Comunications group coordinator - Superintendence of Industry and Commerce.

Alejandra Rodríguez B.

Website Editor
Superintendence of Industry
and Commerce.